Guide to the William Rose Benét Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal and Family Papers, 1847-1950; Series V; 18.76; 26 boxes + 2 art, 1 broadside folder
  - Other Family Papers
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent
      - Printed ephemera, 1939–1947 (Box 97, Folder 3102)
    - Benét, Teresa (Thompson)
      - Autograph, undated (Box 97, Folder 3103)
    - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét)
      - Printed ephemera, 1933–1950 (Box 97, Folder 3104)
      - School records and material, 1925-1927, undated (Box 97, Folder 3105)
    - Fry, Kathleen Anne (Benét)
      - Printed ephemera, 1937 June 12 (Box 97, Folder 3106)
      - School records and material, 1924-1928, undated (Box 97, Folder 3107)
    - Norris, Charles G. (Charles Gilman)
      - Biographical information, undated (Box 97, Folder 3108)
    - Norris, Kathleen
      - Inscription, 1920 (Box 97, Folder 3109)
    - Wylie, Elinor
      - Addresses, undated (Box 97, Folder 3110)
      - Beaded necklace, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Card and other cases, undated (Box 97, Folder 3111-3112)
      - "Certificate of Registration", 1925–1928 (Box 97, Folder 3113)
      - Coins, undated (Box 97, Folder 3114)
      - Crucifix, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Dip pen, undated (Box 97, Folder 3115)
      - "Dispatch" case, undated (Box 99, Folder 3120)
      - Eyeglasses with cases, undated (Box 100 (Cold storage))
        Conditions Governing Access
        Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
      - Eyeglasses case, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Financial records, 1922–1928 (Box 97, Folder 3116-3119)
      - Harmonica with case, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Jewelry with box, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Kerchiefs, undated (Box 101, Folder 3121)
      - Medical records, 1923-1928, undated (Box 101, Folder 3122)
      - Metal figure, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Nibs (pen points) with box, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Notes and notebooks, undated (Box 101, Folder 3123)
      - Pen or pencil case, undated (Box 101, Folder 3124)
      - Pencil erasers and sharpener, undated (Box 101, Folder 3125)
      - Pencils, undated (Box 101, Folder 3126-3127)
      - Photograph albums, 1920s, undated (Box 101, Folder 3128-3129)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 101, Folder 3130)
      - Pill case, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Printed ephemera, 1924, undated (Box 101, Folder 3131)
      - Rubber thimbles with box, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Salt shaker, undated (Box 98 (Art))
      - Silhouette of Percy Bysshe Shelley, undated (Box 101, Folder 3132)
      - Stationery pad and sheet, undated (Box 101, Folder 3133)
      - Thread, undated (Box 101, Folder 3134)
      - Unidentified object, undated (Box 98 (Art))
  - Photographs
    - William Rose Benét
      - Benét, William Rose, 1893-1946, undated (Box 102, Folder 3135-3138)
      - Benét, William Rose with family, [circa 1912]-1940s (Box 102, Folder 3139-3140)
      - Benét, William Rose with others, [circa 1903]-1950, undated (Box 102, Folder 3141-3142)
      - Benét, William Rose with others, 1904, undated (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3396)
      - William Rose Benét in artwork, [1950], undated (Box 102, Folder 3143)
      - Bust of William Rose Benét, [1950] (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3397)
    - Family
      - Baxter, Lora, undated (Box 102, Folder 3144)
      - Baxter, Lora, undated (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3398)
      - Benét children, 1931, undated (Box 102, Folder 3145-3146)
      - Benét children with others, undated (Box 102, Folder 3147)
      - Benét, Frances Rose (mother), 1905, undated (Box 102, Folder 3148)
      - Benét, James, 1914- (son), undated (Box 102, Folder 3149)
      - Benét, James, 1914- (son) with family, undated (Box 103, Folder 3150)
      - Benét, James, 1914- (son) with others, undated (Box 103, Folder 3151)
      - Benét, James Walker (father), 1883, undated (Box 103, Folder 3152)
      - Benét, Juana Hernandez, undated (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3399)
      - Benét, Kathleen Anne (daughter), undated (Box 103, Folder 3153)
      - Benét, Kathleen Anne (daughter) with family, undated (Box 103, Folder 3154)
      - Benét, Kathleen Anne (daughter) with others, undated (Box 103, Folder 3155)
      - Benét, Laurence Vincent (uncle), undated (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3400)
      - Benét, Laurence Vincent (painting), undated (Box 103, Folder 3156)
      - Benét, Pedro, undated (Box 120 (Oversize), Folder 3401)
      - Benét, Stephen Vincent, undated (Box 103, Folder 3157)
      - Benét, Teresa Frances (Thompson), 1883; 1903 (Box 103, Folder 3158)
      - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét) (daughter), undated (Box 103, Folder 3159)
      - Flack, Marjorie, undated (Box 103, Folder 3160)
      - Hoyt, Henry Martyn, undated (Box 103, Folder 3161)
      - Norris, Kathleen with others, undated (Box 103, Folder 3162)
      - Rose, William John (uncle), 1929 (Box 103, Folder 3163)
      - Wylie, Elinor, 1920s (Box 103, Folder 3164)
      - Wylie, Elinor, undated (Box 121 (Oversize), Folder 3402-3403)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 103, Folder 3165)
    - Others
      - Bardwell, Robert D., undated (Box 103, Folder 3166)
      - Bennett, Mark J., undated (Box 103, Folder 3167)
      - Ficke, Gladys Brown, undated (Box 103, Folder 3168)
      - Foster, William E., undated (Box 103, Folder 3169)
      - "Friends", 1937, undated (Box 103, Folder 3170-3172)
      - Hahn, Emily, undated (Box 121 (Oversize), Folder 3404)
      - Hall, ----, undated (Box 103, Folder 3173)
      - Hay, Sara Henderson, undated (Box 103, Folder 3174)
      - Huxley, Aldous, undated (Box 103, Folder 3175)
      - Morley, Christopher, undated (Box 103, Folder 3176)
      - Peck, J. Sherman, undated (Box 103, Folder 3177)
      - Ridge, Lola, 1929 (Box 121 (Oversize), Folder 3405)
      - Stevens, Wallace, [circa 1936] (Box 103, Folder 3178)
      - Thompson, Kathleen, undated (Box 103, Folder 3179)
      - Torrence, Ridgely, undated (Box 103, Folder 3180)
      - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott; Field, Sara Bard, undated (Box 103, Folder 3181)
      - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott; Field, Sara Bard, 1933 June (Box 121 (Oversize), Folder 3406)
      - "Frank", undated (Box 103, Folder 3182)
      - "Mark", [circa 1903] (Box 103, Folder 3183)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 103, Folder 3184)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 121 (Oversize), Folder 3407)
    - Places
      - Burial place, [circa 1950] (Box 103, Folder 3185)
      - "The Firs, Bowerchalke to Salisbury," England, undated (Box 103, Folder 3186)
      - Garden of cottage rented by Elinor Wylie, at Henley-on-Thames, undated (Box 103, Folder 3187)
      - Interior of apartment, 36 West 9th Street, [New York?], undated (Box 103, Folder 3188)
      - "Meads Mountain House", undated (Box 103, Folder 3189)
      - New York City, undated (Box 103, Folder 3190)
      - "Norris's bungalow," Mill Valley, California, 1914 December (Box 103, Folder 3191)
      - Pigeon Cove, Rockport, Massachusetts, undated (Box 104, Folder 3192)
      - Rockport, Massachusetts, undated (Box 104, Folder 3193)
      - Room at Yale, New Haven, Connecticut, [circa 1903-1908] (Box 121 (Oversize), Folder 3408)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 104, Folder 3194)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 121 (Oversize), Folder 3409)
    - Others
      - Albums, undated (Box 104, Folder 3195-3196)
      - Artwork, undated (Box 104, Folder 3197)
      - Christmas photographs, undated (Box 104, Folder 3198)
      - Madonna from home of Carmen Benét, undated (Box 104, Folder 3199)
      - Reference prints from nitrate negatives, undated (Box 104, Folder 3200-3202)
      - Sporting events, undated (Box 104, Folder 3203)
      - Theatrical event, undated (Box 104, Folder 3204)
  - Printed Material
    - Academy of American Poets, 1935-1949, undated (Box 105, Folder 3205)
    - Albany Academy, 1903 (Box 105, Folder 3206)
    - Albany Academy, 1903 (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3410)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1943–1948 (Box 105, Folder 3207)
    - Awards and honors, 1933–1949 (Box 105, Folder 3208)
    - Book jackets, [1931]-[1948] (Box 105, Folder 3209)
    - Brochures, catalogs, and other publicity, 1914-1958, undated (Box 105, Folder 3210-3211)
    - Brochures, catalogs, and other publicity, 1942, undated (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3411)
    - Calendars, 1894 (Box 105, Folder 3212)
    - Calling cards, 1906, undated (Box 105, Folder 3213)
    - Christmas cards, 1935-1947, undated (Box 105, Folder 3214)
    - An Elementary French Grammar by Léon Constanseau, annotated and signed, 1911 (Box 105, Folder 3215)
    - Events and programs, 1899-1950, undated (Box 105, Folder 3216-3217)
    - Events and programs, 1932 August (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3412)
    - "The Forms of Poetry," chart, [1933?] (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3413)
    - General interest and brief mentions, 1926-1946, undated (Box 105, Folder 3218-3219)
    - General interest and brief mentions, 1905–1944 (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3414)
    - Illustrations, undated (Box 106, Folder 3220)
    - Invitations, 1942-1947, undated (Box 106, Folder 3221)
    - Letterhead for Editorial Department, The Century Magazine, undated (Box 106, Folder 3222)
    - Maps, undated (Box 106, Folder 3223)
    - Maps, 1906 (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3415)
    - Maps, 1943 (Box 130 (Broadside))
    - Material relating to Harry Kemp, undated (Box 106, Folder 3224)
    - Memorial tributes, 1944–1950 (Box 106, Folder 3225)
    - Music, 1950, undated (Box 106, Folder 3226)
    - New York Public Library call slips, completed in manuscript, undated (Box 106, Folder 3226a)
    - "The Old Gorsedd Prayer", undated (Box 106, Folder 3227)
    - Pittsburgh in 1816 by the Carnegie Library, 1916 (Box 106, Folder 3228)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 106, Folder 3229)
    - Presentation inscriptions, 1847-1927, undated (Box 106, Folder 3230)
    - Yale College material, 1904-1944, undated (Box 106, Folder 3231-3233)
  - Other Material
    - Address book, undated (Box 106, Folder 3234)
    - Material removed from address book, 1946-1950, undated (Box 106, Folder 3235)
    - Bibliographic information, undated (Box 106, Folder 3236)
    - Biographical information, undated (Box 106, Folder 3237)
    - Brass plate, undated (Box 106, Folder 3238)
    - Calendars and diaries, 1901-1950, undated (Box 107, Folder 3239-3247)
    - Calling card case, undated (Box 108, Folder 3248)
    - "Contents of William Rose Benét's wallet at time of his death", 1942-1950, undated (Box 108, Folder 3249)
    - Empty envelopes, undated (Box 108, Folder 3250)
    - Empty folders, undated (Box 108, Folder 3251)
    - Empty folders, undated (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3416)
    - Genealogical information, undated (Box 108, Folder 3252)
    - Genealogical information, undated (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3417)
    - Invitations, circa 1949 (Box 108, Folder 3253)
    - Itineraries, 1938, undated (Box 108, Folder 3254)
    - Leather wallet, undated (Box 108, Folder 3255)
    - Material removed from wallet, 1930, undated (Box 108, Folder 3256)
    - Letter fragments, 1874 (Box 108, Folder 3257)
    - Lists, undated (Box 108, Folder 3258)
    - Map of San Fancisco, annotated, removed from 1949 diary, undated (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3418)
    - Material relating to the Lamont controversy, 1943-1944, undated (Box 108, Folder 3259-3260)
    - Material relating to the Lamont controversy, 1943, undated (Box 122 (Oversize), Folder 3419)
    - Medallions and pins, undated (Box 108, Folder 3261-3262)
    - Medallions and pins, undated (Box 109, Folder 3263)
    - Membership and identity cards, 1917-1950, undated (Box 109, Folder 3264)
    - Microcard, circa 1950 (Box 109, Folder 3265)
    - Music, undated (Box 109, Folder 3266)
    - Notes and notebooks, undated (Box 109, Folder 3267-3277)
    - Notes and notebooks, undated (Box 110, Folder 3278-3293)
    - Notes and notebooks, undated (Box 111, Folder 3294-3307)
    - Notes and notebooks, undated (Box 112, Folder 3308-3314)
    - "Request for Permission To Reprint", 1946 July 24 (Box 112, Folder 3315)
    - School records, 1899-1908, undated (Box 112, Folder 3316)
    - Scrapbook ("Golf Only"), 1902-1904, undated (Box 112, Folder 3317)
    - Scrapbook, 1904-1907, undated (Box 113, Folder 3319)
    - Stamps, undated (Box 112, Folder 3318)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, Series VI; 3.25; 4 boxes
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - In Series I (Box 131, Folder 3424-3509)
  - In Series II - Series III (Box 132, Folder 3510-3575)
  - In Series III - Series IV (Box 133, Folder 3576-3638)
  - In Series I - Series II (Box 135 (Oversize), Folder 3639-3648)